英文片名：The.Descent 中文片名：黑暗侵襲
(女孩們的笑聲)
(Girls laughing)
快點！
Come on!
(尖叫聲)
(Shrieking)
女孩們，小心了, 我們走了. (尖叫聲)
Look out girls, here we go. (Shrieks)
小心左邊 .
Look to the left.
划槳!
Paddle!
你能看到他嗎?  媽咪!
Can you see her?  Mummy!
(尖叫聲)
(Shrieking)
來吧！
Come on!
穩住!
Hold on!
天啦！
Christ!
爽!
Yes!
媽咪!  孩子們!
Mummy!  Hi, guys!
哦，傑斯. 耶!
Oh, Jessie. Yeah!
(笑聲) 這太不可思議了
(Laughs) That was amazing.
(女孩們笑)
(Girls laugh)
哦，你們女孩子在尖叫.  你還好嗎，傑斯?
Oh, you girls were screaming.  All right, Jessie?
不算太壞, 不是嗎?  是的, 跟撒泡尿一樣容易
That wasn't so bad, was it?  No, it was a piece of piss.
哇哦!
Whoo!
他媽的!
Bitch!
再來一點，再來一點   保羅，過來把他拉上來！
Bit more, bit more.  Go on, Paul. Fish her out.
拉到你了!~
There. Got you.
你沒事吧？  是.
You all right?  Yeah.
冷死了，我手指都沒感覺了.
lt's freezing. l can't feel my fingers.
天啦!
Heave!
天啦.
Jessie, Jessie.
哦，到這兒來. 哦，寶貝兒
Ah, come here. Oh, babe.
剛才太爽了. 你也喜歡這種運動嗎?
lt wasjust amazing. Would you like to do that?
傑斯,過來，太冷了！ 我們到車上去吧
Come on, Jessie, it's freezing. Let's go back to the car.
跟著你的老爸.
Go with your Daddy.
我來幫一下女孩們.  好吧t.
l'll just help the girls.  All right.
不要緊,你自己忙吧，這兒我們自己能應付
lt's OK, you go on. We can finish up here.
你確定? 夥計們謝謝. 旅館見！
You sure? Thanks, guys. l'll see you at the hotel.
再見.
See you.
傑斯, 我需要打電話給雷切爾的媽嗎?
Jess, shall l phone Rachel's mum?
看雷切爾 是否想在星期四來吃飯?
See if Rachel wants to come to dinner on Thursday?
好
Yeah? OK.
過來後, 她可以幫我們準備生日聚會.
When she comes round, she can help us plan your birthday party.
這次你想邀請男生嗎?  (笑聲)
Are you going to invite any boys this time?  (Laughs)
你沒事吧? Y你看起來有點冷漠.
Are you OK? You seem a bit distant.
我好著呢.
l'm fine.
(急剎車聲)
(Tyres screech)
(監控設備聲)
(Monitor beeps)
(Flatline t0ne)
(Flatline tone)
傑斯?
Jess?
傑斯!
Jessie!
(Panting)
傑斯!
Jessie!
對不起，她已經去世了
Sh, sh. l'm sorry. She's gone.
對不起  不!
l'm sorry.  No!
不.
No, no.
No, no, no.
他死了, 莎拉.
She's gone, Sarah. Shh.
(失聲痛哭)
(Wails)  Shh.
(Banjo music)
(音樂轉到福音書)  這是泥土, 血和啤酒...
(Music changes to gospel)  Well, it's mud, blood and beer...
或者 敬愛的耶穌.
or sweet Jesus.
好極了. 把那個他媽的關了.
Great. Turn that shite off.
這令人恐懼
That's frightening.
聽著，我們不必這麼做的，這你是知道的
Listen, we don't have to do this, you know.
我們可以掉頭回去呆在鎮上。
We can head back and stay in town.
說著廢話，去那些庸俗的舞會.
Get wasted, go to a barn dance.
既然令人恐懼.
Now that is frightening.
你說的對，我們不必這麼做。 但我不是那個告訴朱諾的人.
You're right, we don't have to do this. But l'm not going to be the one to tell Juno.
他有一份工作，男人. 她總是把我們帶到中央...
She's a piece of work, man. She always brings us out into the middle of...
好吧，看著吧
Well, look at it.
她去年來蘇格蘭。  是的，來去匆匆.
She came to Scotland last year.  Yeah, and left pretty quickly.
哦
(Whoops)
莎啦! 貝思!
Sarah! Beth!
朱諾.
Juno.
你看起來好酷.
You look fantastic.
啊，到這兒來.
Ah, come here. Oh.
讓我好好看看你. 哇!
Let me look at you. Wow!
一切都會好起來的.
Everything is going to be fine.
會更好.
Better. lt's going to be great.
貝卡和 薩姆急切的想見你. 你為什麼不呢?
Becca and Sam can't wait to see you. Why don't you go in?
我來提.  好.
Give me these.  Yeah.
謝謝.
Thanks.
好嗎?  好.
OK?  Yeah, OK.
哦，非常好
Ooh, very nice.
她怎麼樣?  她就在這兒.
How is she?  Well, she's here.
一步一步輕輕走?
One step at a time, eh?
喂! 你說誰是他媽的騙子?
Hey, hey, hey! Who are you calling a fucking cheater?
說你呢！
l'm calling you a fucking cheater.
哈羅!
Hello!
哈羅
Hey!
Hello.
你看起來真是特別好  哦，你看起來太令人驚訝了.
You do look really good.  Oh, you look amazing.
Hey!  我先把包放下.
Hey!  Let me put the bags down.
見到你真高興.
Oh, so nice to see you.
我們餓了.  好吧，去吃飯把.
We're starving.  OK, go, go.
你得到什麼了?  哦，一些...
What have you got?  Er, well, there's a bit of...
薩姆.薩姆.
Sam. Sam.
謝謝你寫信給我. 他對我幫助很大.
Thank you so much for your letter. lt meant a lot to me.
哦，莎啦, 沒能去那兒我很抱歉.
Oh, Sarah, look, l'm so sorry that l couldn't be there.
你知道的，期中..
You know, midterms and...
你知道的, 薩姆差不多一年之後 就會 跟文萊博士一樣
You know, Sam is going to be Doctor Van Ney in like a year's time.
不!
No!
告訴我會比這個時間長?  我對我的小妹很有信心.
Please tell me it's longer than that?  l am so proud of my little sister.
誰要飲料?  我要
Who wants a drink?  Yes! Me!
白蘭地?  好啊.
Brandy shot?  Yeah, yeah.
那麼, 貝絲你呢...  什麼?
So, Beth...  Mmhm?
我聽到有超過25的酒全部分解了?
l hear it all starts falling apart past 25?
這就是你在醫學院學到的嗎？ 就這麼簡單?
ls that what they teach you at medical school, yeah? To take the piss?
無恥的婊子!  啊哦!
Cheeky bitch!  Ow!
有誰能讓我感覺成熟一點?
Can anyone make me feel any older?
哦，我們走. 哈羅.
Oh, here we go.  Hello.
咳，你一定會成為老師.  貝思 莎啦, 這是霍莉.
Hi, you must be the teacher.  Beth, Sarah, this is Holly.
朱諾 罩著的
Juno's protege.
我總是以為朱諾會在年輕的時候吃了她.  太好了.
l always thought Juno would eat her young.  Oh, nice.
我能控制好我自己。 謝謝.
l'm well able to handle myself, thanks very much.
我聽說過你. 你是違心到可以跳樓的人.
l've heard about you. You're that mentalist that jumps off buildings.
基礎跳躍.你真的應該試一下.  你現在住在美國?
Base jumping. You should try it, seriously.  So you live in America now?
用盡所有的 東西穿著戈爾韋粗法蘭絨開始吧, 你知道的.
Ran out of things to jump off in Galway, you know.
我總是尋找下一個更高的目標
l'm always searching for the next big high.
當然這你應該知道  不好意思?
Sure you'd know all about that.  Sorry?
朱諾給我看過一張照片 是你們一起爬山時拍的
Juno showed me a photo of when you used to climb together.
啊，我找到這個經典的照片了!
l found this classic picture. Ah!
不!  不!
Oh, no!  Oh, no!
看我們的狀態!  天啦，這太差了.
Look at the state of us!  Oh, my God. That's bad.
性感!
Sexy!
愛上每一天.
Love each day.
這不是保羅常說的嗎？.
Used to be something Paul used to say.
不管怎樣...乾杯
Anyway...cheers.
為我們的探險.
Here's to our adventure.
乾杯
Skol.  Cheers.
借火, 你這個混蛋
Come on, light, you bastard.
那麼，你以前去過山洞穴嗎?
So, have you done Boreham Caverns before?
我曾經在一本書上看到 它是旅遊勝地，不是用來探險的.
l saw it in a book once. lt's for tourists. lt's not adventure.
也許還有扶手 還有他媽的禮品店.
Might as well have hand rails and a fucking gift shop.
如果你集洞穴工作者，攀登者，跳高者...於一身
lf you're a caver, jumper, climber...
你只需按部就班，就像拉泡屎一樣簡單
..you just do it and not give a shite.
除非東西比你能得到的還大.
Or the thing that's bigger than you will get you.
朱諾: 霍莉，你嚮往探險? 我什麼時候讓你失望過?
JUNO: You want adventure, Holly? When have l ever let you down?
什麼?
What?
霍麗, 明天將會很可怕嗎？
Holly, tomorrow is going to be awesome. OK?
帶上這個，你需要的.
Take this. You need it.  (Chuckles)
莎啦: 薩姆， 喬希怎麼樣? 你們還在一起嗎?
SARAH: What about Josh, Sam? Are you guys still together?
薩姆: 有幾分
SAM: Kind of. Sort of.
不同...改變.
Different...shifts.
天啦！
Oh, my God.
天啦  呃，你是怎麼想的?
Oh, my Jesus!  What do you think, eh?
(Laughter)
他媽的能不能別說話?
Don't say a fucking word, all right?
它是聖誕禮物
lt was a Christmas present.
閉嘴.
Shut up.
霍麗，你呢?飯了一個小白臉?  奧。
What about you Holly? Got a man?  Oh...
跟朱諾一樣，我全身心的投入體育運動中.
l'm a sports fuck like Juno.
什麼？  我想麗貝卡也是吧
What?  Rebecca, too, l think.
可是當我老了 我想有一大堆的孩子.
HOLLY: But when l'm older, l want to have lots of babies.
貝絲, 莎啦是不是告訴過你...
JUNO: Beth, did Sarah tell you that...
(Birds calling)
(Wind chimes)
哦
(Knock at door)  Oh!
起床了.
Wakey.
我感覺想馬路殺手一樣. 再給我5分鐘.
l feel like road kill. Give me five minutes.
5分鐘.
Five minutes.
(Screams)
早上好,孩子們. 起床了。
Good morning, my little ones. Wakey, wakey.
早上好  吵什麼? 他媽的都凍僵了!
Good morning.  ls that what you call it? lt's fucking freezing!
霍麗!
Holly!
我們七點出發，別遲到.
We're leaving at seven. Don't be late.
盡量吧
Try that.
皇后睡的跟死豬一樣
The queen is dead.
長久..去他媽的皇后.
Long live...the fucking queen.
(Laughter)
貝絲, 你不會要開車吧
JUNO: Beth, you're not driving.
你開車的話，我們永遠不會到達.  ,剪刀,石頭，布
lf you drive we'll never get there.  Paper, scissors, stone.
快點  你就是大混蛋。.
Come on.  Oh, you're a dick.
來吧  好了.
Go on.  OK.
你先出.  不，等一下. 三回合定勝負.
There you go.  No, wait, babe. Best of three.
我來開車，好嗎？
l'll drive. Right?
女士們，集體拍照
Ladies, group photo.
你最好快一點，我們快遲到了
You'd better hurry it up. We're running late.
我看起來糟透了  我們都是. 笑一個.
l look like shit.  We all look like shit. Just give me a smile.
要不要取下帽子?  .取下
Hat? No hat?  No hat.
取下帽子  好了.
No hat, no hat.  All right.
快，快，快  說『』茄子『』
Run, run, run, run.  Say ''sausage''!
茄子！
ALL: Sausage!
莎啦 ，稍微減點速.  我正在陶醉之中.
Sarah, slow down a bit.  l'm having fun.
她正爽著呢.
She's having fun.
哦，轉彎，就在那兒轉彎!
Whoa! Turn, turn, turn there.
咱們越野吧  太棒了.
Let's off road.  Great.
你應該喝一點水.
You should have some water.
調節這個表是不可能的 按鈕真他媽的太小了.
Trying to set this watch is impossible. The buttons are too fucking small.
不要管它.  那你為什麼戴著它呢?
Leave it alone.  Why do you wear it, anyway?
我男朋友送給我的，觸景生情啊.  去他媽的感情.
My boyfriend gave it to me, it's sentimental.  lt's fucking mental.
不管是誰送給我，我都會把它撇了
Any guy that gave that to me, l'd dump him.
朱諾， 你確定我們路走對了嗎？
BETH: Juno, are you sure this is the right way?
放鬆。我從未迷過路.  了不起啊.
Relax, l've never been lost in my life.  Marvellous.
那麼你以前有沒有去過山洞穴?  沒有.
So have you done these caves before?  No.
但是它們沒什麼難度 相當安全，別擔心.
But they are only level two. Quite safe, don't worry.
我沒擔心什麼.  唯一的危險是我可能會睡著了.
l wasn't.  The only danger is that l might fall asleep.
伯瑞漢姆巨洞. 更像是伯瑞敦姆巨洞
Boreham Caves. More like boredom caves.
停的好.  多謝.
Nice parking.  Thanks.
這一次在蓋耳崴，. 當我自助爬教堂時,
HOLLY: This one time in Galway. when l freeclimbed the cathedral,
神父追著我 一直到底樓.
a priest chased me down the whole of the ground floor.
太爽了.
That was brilliant.
雖然我笨不應該白費力氣的 霍麗，閉嘴.
l shouldn't have wasted the effort, though. REBECCA: Holly, shut up.
麗貝卡, 別理她.
Rebecca, leave her alone.
姑娘們，走了. 快來不及了.
OK, guys, let's get moving. We're running late.
趕快，跟上.
SAM: Come on, keep up.
霍麗，等一等. 懶蟲，快走.
SAM: Hey, Holly, wait up. REBECCA: Move it, short arse.
哦，卡特，跟在後面. 趕快，你這混蛋
BETH: Oi, Carter, get to the back. HOLLY: Come on, you lazy bastard.
你終於趕上我了.
JUNO: You finally caught up with me.
朱諾，我們到了嗎?  前面半公里處有一條小河.
Juno, are we there yet?  There's a river about half a mile ahead.
到了之後, 我們順流而上就到了洞口,不是嗎?
When we reach it, we follow it up to the mouth of the cave, OK?
她怎麼知道前面有一條小河? 我不同意.
How does she know there's a river up ahead? l can't hear a thing.
她是聞到的.
She can probably smell it.
他上周來這兒 探過路.
She came up here last week to check the route out.
這是第一原則 起草一份奮鬥計劃然後堅持到底.
lt's rule number one  file a flight plan and stick to it.
第二原則？?  不要迷路.
And rule number two?  Don't go wandering off.
你以為只有你熄燈後才會變黑呀. 下面都是漆黑的.
You think it's dark when you turn out the lights. Well, down there it's pitch black.
你可能會拖水，失去方向感...  好了好了.
You can get dehydration, disorientation...  Yeah, yeah, yeah.
..得幽閉恐怖癥...  別廢話了.
..claustrophobia...  Blah, blah.
..無緣無故被襲擊, 妄想, 幻覺,
..panic attacks, paranoia, hallucinations,
視覺，聽覺，退化...
visual and aural deterioration...
(Squawking)
喂
Hey!
哦
Eurgh.
耶，霍麗，親愛的。真正的拍照時間到了.
Yeah, lovely, Holly. A real Kodak moment.
不要碰它. 你不會想滾蛋吧.
Don't touch it.  You wouldn't want to piss it off.
薩姆，你怎麼看這個？一隻熊嗎？
What do you think did that, Sam? A bear?
這是什麼？天生的偵探?
What is this? Nature Detectives?
這兒應該有大足印的. 來吧.  薩姆，不要用他媽的樹枝刺它.
lt could have been Big Foot. Come on.  Sam, stop poking it with a fucking stick.
到了.
This is it.
你開玩笑吧!  恐怕不是.
You're having a laugh!  Afraid not.
我是英語教師, 不是盜墓的.
l'm an English teacher, not fucking Tomb Raider.
你會沒事的 .
You'll be fine.
好了，莎拉，貝思，你們下一個上. 薩姆跟 貝卡呆在一起.
JUNO: OK, Sarah, Beth, you're up next. Sam, stay with Becca.
跟著他做，你會沒事的.
Do what she does and you'll be fine.
霍麗，安全第一. 我不想這次有任何閃失.
Holly, safety first. l don't want any stunts this time.
你沒事吧?下面見.
You OK? See you down there.  No.
確保你的牛皮繩綁好了  你像這樣抓住它.
REBECCA: Make sure your cow's tail is locked there and there. You hold on to this like that.
看，我以前做過，你不知道嗎
Look, l have done this before, you know?
我只是照顧你而已. 我感謝你，稍微.
l'm only looking after you.  And l appreciate it, in small doses.
你必須看看地方.
JUNO: You gotta see this place.
太美
lt's beautiful!
貝思，你絕對不會相信.  媽的!
JUNO: You won't believe this, Beth.  Oh, shit!
天啦.
Shit, shit, shit.
哦，天啦。打死我我也想不到
Oh, my God, l'm gonna die.
(Panting)
太容易了.
Ah, piece of piss.
天啦
Oh, my God!
難以置信
lt's incredible.
安全!
(Shouts up) Clear!
(Shrieks) BETH: lt's Holly.
媽的，走
Shit, move!
霍麗，在我的帶領下安全，有秩序的來，好嗎？
Holly, you do this safely, in order, following my lead. OK?
放鬆，慢點.
Take it slow and easy.
朱諾，.  你很靈巧
HOLLY: Juno.  Smart arse.
(Screeching)
(Screams)
沒事了.
lt's OK. lt's OK. lt's OK.
它們飛走了。它們已經飛走了，不信你看.
They're gone. They're gone now. Look.
一隻蝙蝠,兩隻蝙蝠 ........
HOLLY: (As The Count) One bat, two bats.
50只 .
50 bats.
(Grunts)
霍麗，滾開.
Holly, fuck off.
哪一條路?
Which way?
離開這兒只有一條路 那就是順著繩子向下 .
There's only one way out of this chamber and that's down the pipe.
好了.
OK.
是一滴水.
JUNO: lt's a drop.
(Clattering)
什麼?
JUNO: OK?
霍麗，打開你的包
JUNO: Holly, chuck us your bag.
(Fizzing)
天啦
SARAH: Oh, my God!  (Laughter)
(Squeaking)
(Water dripping)
有什麼發現沒?
(Laughs) Find anything good?
耶穌啊  來吧，我們吃點東西吧.
Jesus Christ!  Come on, let's eat.
霍麗，你休息一下嗎?  我只想在深入下去.
Holly, would you take a break?  l just want to take a few more shots.
著山東比我想像的要冷.
This cave is a lot cooler than l thought.
嗨?
Hey?
我不餓.
Not hungry.
沒事吧?
Are you OK?
朱諾，我不會半途而廢的，我好得很.
Juno, l won't break. l'm fine.
我問你吃不吃  我知道.
l asked you for this.  l know.
呃，莎拉?
Um, Sarah?
我一直沒有機會說我......
l haven't had a chance to say that l'm...
我沒有在事故後多陪你一段時間
really sorry l didn't stay around longer after the accident.
不管怎樣...
Anyway...
..現在我們全在這兒彌補，行嗎?
..we're all here for you now, OK?
嗯.
Yeah.
我現在感覺有點力不從心. 可能是時差反映吧.
Look, sorry. l'm feeling a bit out of it. lt's probably jet lag.
我四處看看，好嗎?  好.
So l'm just going to take a look around, OK?  Yeah, OK.
為什麼不幫我們談一下路呢?
Why don't you try and find us the way through, huh?
嗨，不要走太遠.
Hey, don't go too far.
他怎麼呢? 她看起來像撞見鬼了.
What's up with her? She looks like she's seen a ghost.
她沒事
She's fine.
(Water dripping)
我發現新大陸了!
l've found the next passage!
就是這兒?它有點小，不是嗎?  嗨，嗨!
That's it? lt's a bit small, isn't it?  Hey, hey, hey!
這不是我想要的. 什麼?
l don't get this.  What?
著跟我叢書上看到 的不一樣
This is not how l imagined it from reading the book.
這就是為什麼我不相信書. 留下了太多的想像空間.
That's why l don't trust books. Leaves too much room for interpretation.
有問題嗎？
Something wrong?
沒有.  好著呢.
No.  lt's nothing.
姑娘們，我去探路.
HOLLY: l'm taking point, guys.
小心。只要找到通過的路. 我們在這兒等著.
Careful. Just find the way through. We'll wait here.
(Splashing through water)
(Echoing laughter)
(Laughter)
莎拉?
Sarah?
媽的.  你還是跟在我後面嗎？
Shit.  Are you still behind me?
對.
Yes.
媽的!
Shit!
(Strains with exertion) Shit!
莎拉? 姑娘們，是莎拉，她可能卡住了.
Sarah? Guys, it's Sarah, l think she might be stuck.
我被卡住了!
l am stuck!
BETH:沒事的，莎拉. 鎮靜，放鬆.
BETH: All right, Sarah. Calm down, just relax.
(Grunts)
我他媽的不能放鬆.
l can't fucking relax.
媽的
Fuck, fuck!
莎拉，你必須鎮定下來， 你唯一要做的就是呼吸.
Sarah, you have to calm down and the only way you're going to do that is to breathe.
好，慢慢的呼吸，保持呼吸
OK, breathe slowly. Just keep breathing.
(Sarah struggles for breath)
我做不到.
l can't. l can't.
我他媽不能呼吸. 莎拉，聽我說.
l can't fucking breathe.  Sarah, OK, listen to me.
只聽我說，好嗎?
Just listen to my voice, yeah?
莎拉，我來了. 好嗎？
Sarah, l'm coming. l'm coming back. OK? OK.
莎拉，你沒事吧?
Sarah, OK?
聽我的，保持呼吸
Listen to me, keep breathing. OK? Hey.
喂，喂.
Hey, hey.
好了.
OK. OK. OK.
看我這兒，莎拉，好嗎?  幫我.
Look here at me, Sarah, hey?  Help me.
傻啦，你擔心什麼呢? 看著我.
What are you so worried about, Sarah? Look at me.
呼吸，呼吸，好嗎?
OK, breathe. Breathe, OK?
喂，喂，喂，聽我的.
Hey, hey, hey. Listen to me.
聽我說，你怕什麼呢?  我動不了!
Listen to me. What are you so afraid of?  l can't fucking move!
你可以的。莎拉，看著我.
You can move. Sarah, look at me, look at me.
最壞的情況已經發生了， 你不還好好的嗎
The worst thing that could have happened to you has already happened and you're still here.
我發誓,這僅僅是一個山洞 誒有什麼值得害怕的
This is just a poxy cave and there's nothing left to be afraid of, l promise.
好嗎？
OK? OK?
嗨嗨，聽我說.
Hey. Hey, listen, listen.
聽我說，你會喜歡這個的. 您怎麼給檸檬性交高潮?
Listen to me, you'll love this one. How do you give a lemon an orgasm?
媽的，讓我聽你重複它 您怎麼給檸檬性交高潮?
God damn it, let me hear you say it. How do you give a lemon an orgasm?
你作什麼呢? 你您發癢它的柑橘.
What do you do? You tickle its citrus. (Laughs)
好點了嗎？. 來.
OK, that's better. Come on.
好，我們要走了. 抓住我的胳膊好嗎?
OK, OK. All right, we're going to move now. Take hold of my arm, all right?
我們將會緩慢的移動. 就這樣，拽住我胳膊?
We're going to move slowly. That's it, grab my arm, OK?
好，來吧.
OK, come on.
慢慢的，拽住我? 好了，走.
Just slowly. Pull on me, OK? OK, come on.
包. 我忘了裝繩子的包.
The rope bag. l forgot the rope bag.
好.
OK.
(Rumbling and crashing)
去他媽的包, 現在就走
OK, fuck the rope bag. OK, move, now!
立刻!
Now!
趕快!
Hurry up!
莎拉，快點!
Sarah, come on!
莎拉, 拽住繩子!
Sarah, keep hold of the rope!
(Muffled coughing)
莎拉?
(Coughing) BETH: Sarah?
恩.
Oh, ah.
你沒事吧?  我很好.
Are you OK?  l'm all right.
所有人都好吧
JUNO: ls everybody OK? ls everybody OK?
他媽的別碰我. 麗貝卡?
Don't fucking touch me. SAM: Rebecca?
REBECCA: 我在這兒,我沒事. 貝斯,你受傷了嗎?
REBECCA: l'm here, l'm OK. Beth, are you injured?
沒有,我很好.
No, l'm fine.
在坍塌結束前不要輕舉妄動.  別擔心,朱諾,我們哪兒也不去.
Nobody move until the dust has settled.  Don't worry, Juno, we're not going anywhere.
(Coughing)
你可能是對的.
HOLLY: You might be right about that.
耶穌啊.
REBECCA: Jesus.
現在怎麼辦?
HOLLY: So what's the story now?
REBECCA:根據導遊書來說, 這個洞有三條出口.
REBECCA: According to the guidebook, this cave system has three ways out.
這僅僅是一條. 朱諾,是這樣的嗎?
This is just one of them. lsn't that right, Juno?
朱諾,是這樣的,不是嗎?
Juno, that's right, isn't it?
查書.
Check the book.
我沒帶.  什麼?
l didn't bring it.  What?
N0 p0int.
No point.
朱諾,看在上帝的份上.
For Christ's sake, Juno.
我知道.我知道這不對.
l knew it. l knew this wasn't right.
你不是起草了山區救援計劃嗎？ 如果受不到我們的回話的話，他們回過來救我們.
You filed a flight plan to mountain rescue? lf we don't report in, they'll come looking for us.
這就是它應該起的作用 除非我提出一個伯瑞漢姆巨洞的奮鬥計劃
That's how it's supposed to work except l put in a flight plan for Boreham Caverns
朱諾，這不是伯瑞漢姆巨洞，是嗎？
and this isn't Boreham Caverns, is it, Juno?
我們他媽的走錯山洞了?
We're in the wrong fucking cave?
霍麗是對的. 伯瑞漢姆巨洞是一個打著旅遊旗號的陷阱。
Holly was right. Boreham Caverns was a tourist trap.
不要血口噴人!  這不是探險. 這是一次自私的旅行.
Don't try and pin this fucking shite on me!  This is not caving. This is an ego trip.
麗貝卡, 我不知道會搞成這樣.
JUNO: Rebecca, l didn't know this was going to happen.
這就是我們堅信的.
This is exactly what we believe in.
我們說過，, 如果沒有一點風險, 有什麼意思?
We said, if there's no risk, what's the point?
不要試著證明這是對的.
Don't try and justify this.
我們在哪兒？
Where... Where are we?
他還沒有名字. 這是一個新大陸.
lt hasn't got a name. lt's a new system.
我希望我們所有人都來探索.
l wanted us all to discover it.
從未有人下來過.
Noone's ever been down here before.
你他媽在欺騙我.  天啦
You're fucking kidding me.  Oh, God!
我們怎麼才能離開這兒?  可能沒有出路了.
BETH: How the hell do we get out? HOLLY: There may not be a way out.
看來我們不能原路返回了.
JUNO: Look, there's no going back now.
我們的著一條路出去 要抓緊時間.
We have to find a way out of this chamber and keep pushing forward.
BETH: 你他媽以為你再做什麼?
BETH: What the fuck do you think you're doing?
我們全都相信你.  你說這會對莎拉有很大幫助的.
We all trusted you. You told me this was going to be good for Sarah.
你知道她經歷了什麼嗎?
Have you any idea what she's been through?
不, 因為你不能足夠快地離開, 你這個自私鬼.
No, cos you couldn't get away fast enough, you selfish cow.
貝絲,你知道什麼呀?
JUNO: You know what, Beth?
在坍塌中我們都有損失.
We all lost something in that crash.
帶我們離開這兒.
Just get us out of here.
山洞有時會坍塌. 不過概率很低.
JUNO: Look, cave systems sometimes break ground. lt's a small chance.
但是如果我們帶在這兒,我們都會完蛋.
But if we stay here, we'll die.
走吧.
Let's go.
(Falling rubble)
等一下!  怎麼了?
JUNO: Wait!  What?
薩姆,不要動. 不要動.
Don't move, Sam. Just don't move.
呆在那兒.
Stay right there.
媽的. 沒路了.
Oh, shit. No more.
(Falling stone)  Thanks, Beth.
現在我知道有多深了.
Now l know how far down it is.
那麼,現在怎麼辦?
So, what now?
我們中的一個人得到對面 那樣的話她可以為你們加一條繩子.
One of us has to get all the way across there so they can rig a line for you guys.
我有三個凸輪, 我至少還要三個. 其它的繩包那兒去了?
l have three cams, l need at least three more. Where's the other rope bag?
哪兒去了?
Where is it?
山東坍塌的時候,我們弄丟了.
We lost it, when the cave collapsed.
對不起.
Sorry.
幫我一下.
Help me.
(Shallow breathing)
(Grunting)
貝卡,快點.
Come on, Becca.
(Grunting)
Aargh!  You got it.
趕快.
Come on, come on.
麗貝卡,趕快.
JUNO: Come on, Rebecca.
Come on, Rebecca.
你還等什麼呢?
What are you waiting for?
媽的.  你沒事吧?
Fuck.  Are you OK?
出什麼問題了?
What's wrong?
沒事,我好著呢.
lt's nothing. l'm all right.
好.
OK.
(Gasps in frustration)
(Gasps)
好了, 松一點繩子.
(Breathless) All right, more slack.
松一點繩子,謝謝.
More slack, thanks.
(Gasps)
媽的!
Fuck!
(Panting)
媽的
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
好了. 幹得好.
OK. JUNO: Well done.
好了. 把繩子的另一頭扔給我.
(Breathless) OK. Throw me the right rope.
好.
OK.
快.
Come on.
耶!
Yeah!
你讓它看起來容易.  嗯,你讓它看起來困難
Now, you make it look easy.  Yeah, well, you make it look hard.
哦. Beth,不要往下看.一直走.
Oh. JUNO: Don't look down, Beth. Keep going.
一直走. 你沒事的,你很安全
Just keep going. REBECCA: You're OK. You're safe.
好. 你到了.
Good. There you go.
這是關於我還是你?
Was this about me or you?
我們, 回到我們過去的樣子.
lt's about us, getting back to what we used to be.
我希望我們證實這個地方,並給它命名.
l wanted us to claim this place, name it.
我想可能是你的名字.
l thought maybe your name.
或者是我們的.
Or maybe yours.
你做得不錯,趕快.
REBECCA: You're doing well. Come on.
趕快.
Come on.
你到了. 來吧,把手給我.
There you are. Come on, give me your hand.
(Grunting)
(Unhooks cam)
朱諾?
Juno?
我們的所有東西都派得上用場.
We'll need everything we've got.
拉緊.
Haul it in.
媽的.
Fuck.
(Grunts)
好!
Yes!
(Grunts)
伸出手.
Reach.
伸出手
Reach out.
Aargh!
朱諾!
Juno!
不
No!
(Screams)
朱諾,沒事的,我們會拉住你的.
BETH: Juno, it's OK, we've got you.
好了,拉!
OK, pull!
(Grunting)
薩姆! 霍麗, 讓我來.
BETH: Sam! SAM: Holly, let me pass.
麗貝卡, 把手給我們檢查一下.
SAM: Rebecca, show me your hand.
(Groaning)
我們走.
Let go, let go.
這是什麼意思?  我們不是第一批到這兒的人.
What does it mean?  lt means we're not the first.
這是巖釘,對嗎?
lt's a piton, right?
如果他們還在這兒的話, 我們會有更大的機會出去.
lf cavers were here, there's a better chance of us getting out.
這件裝備至少也有100年的歷史. 沒有人會再用這樣的東西了.
This equipment is at least 1 00 years old. Noone uses stuff like this any more.
而且, 如果有人曾經下來過 並且成功出去了,
Besides, if anyone had been down here and made it out,
這個山洞就應該有名字了.
they would have named it already.
(Groaning)
貝卡, 你還好嗎?
JUNO: Becca, are you OK?
死不了.
l'll live.
霍麗, 看起來怎麼樣?
Holly, how does it look?
又變窄了, 不過我還能過.
lt's tight again, but l can get through.
好,繼續走. 我們馬上就跟上來了.
OK, keep going. We'll be right behind you.
下面有些東西.
HOLLY: Hey, there's something down here.
姑娘們,太令人驚奇了 可是我們手電的電池快沒電了.
Guys, it's amazing, but the batteries on our lights will run out.
我建議我們一直走.  等一下.
So l suggest we keep moving.  Wait a minute. Wait.
貝絲,怎麼了?  朱諾,點一根你的火焰棒.
What is it, Beth?  Juno, light up one of your flares.
我們沒時間耗在這兒.  點一根你的火焰棒.
We don't have time for this.  Just light a flare.
貝絲,真的可愛, 可他媽的沒用嘛.  不,看著它,你看到什麼了?
Really lovely, Beth, but it's fucking useless.  No, look at it. What do you see?
你會看到山, 山洞 ...
You've got the mountain, the cave...
有兩個出口.
and there's two entrances.
你真是他媽的天才.  老虎總有發威的時候.
You are a fucking genius.  l have my moments.
這說明還有一條出去的路?  讓我們找出來吧.
This means there's another way out?  Let's find out.
趕快!
Come on!
婊子養的!  走哪一條路?
Bastard!  Which way?
霍麗,把你的打火機給我.
Holly, give me your lighter.
快.  給.
Come on.  Here.
媽的!
Fuck!
快  狗屎!
Come on! Come on!  Shit!
這條路!  喂,霍麗!
That one!  Hey! Holly!
,霍麗,慢一點!
Holly, slow down!
小心,霍麗
JUNO: Holly! Careful!
太陽光,我看到太陽光了!
HOLLY: Daylight! l can see daylight!
霍麗,小心,慢點
Holly! Careful! Slow down!
霍麗,這不是太陽光
Holly, it's not daylight!
救命!  穩住!
Help me!  Hold on!
活計,拽住 ...
Guys! Hold...
霍麗!
Holly!
薩姆,到著下面來
Sam! Get down here!
霍麗!
Holly!
霍麗! 回答我!
Holly! Answer me!
開來我腿受傷了!
l think l hurt my leg!
不要動!我們下來救你來了.
Don't move! We're coming down to you.
哦,媽的
Oh, fuck!
不,媽的
(Screams) No! Fuck!
(Groans)
最好有人下來!
Someone better get down here!
真他媽噁心.  貝絲,不是現在,不是這兒!
Oh, that's fucking disgusting.  Beth! Not here, not now!
我們得幫忙.每人抓住一角. 我們得把她從水中移走.
We need help. Everybody grab a corner. We need to move her out of the water.
好了,輕輕的. 抬!
Nice and easy now. And...lift!
Argh!
你混蛋!  朱諾,去找些東西製作一個夾板.
You fuckers!  Juno, find something to make a splint out of.
好了,我抓住她了.  朱諾,利用一個軸
lt's OK, l've got her.  Hey, Juno, use one of the ice axes.
你會好起來的,甜心.
SAM: You'll be all right, sweetheart.
(Child laughs)
好了.
OK.
莎拉!  朱諾,沃需要你在這兒幫忙.
Sarah!  Juno, l'm gonna need your help here.
莎拉!  朱諾!
Sarah!  Juno!
抓住她的胳膊. 呆會兒你得按住她.
Take hold of her arm. You'll have to hold her down.
你要幹什麼?
What are you gonna do?
我得給你包紮傷口,固定上夾板 但在骨頭突出的時候沒法做.
l need to dress the wound and rig up a splint, but l can't while the bone is protruding.
我得把骨頭壓回去.
l need to push it back in.
恨死你了.  我知道.
l hate you.  l know.
作吧.
Do it.
咬住這個.
Bite down on this.
壓住她.  他媽的咬住別放,好嗎?
Keep hold of her.  Just fucking bite down, OK?
開始!
Go!  (Screams)
來吧!
Come on!
(Holly screams in distance)
寶貝,咬住了.
Just keep biting down, baby.
來吧.
Come on.
什麼人遞給我一個急救包.
OK, someone get me a medical kit.
好了.冷靜.會好起來的
OK, OK, OK. Calm down. lt'll be all right.
(Gasps)
(Panting)
(Gasps)  What are you doing?
我看到隧道前面有一些東西.
l just saw something ahead in the tunnel.
沙拉,我對你發誓, 我要帶你離開這兒.
Sarah, l promise you, l'm gonna get you out of here.
可是你不配合的話我就無能為力了.
But l can't do it unless you're with me.
莎拉?
Sarah?
莎拉!
Sarah!
莎拉,看著我.
Sarah, look at me.
這兒什麼也沒有.
There's nothing there.
這是我能做得最好的啦.
That's the best l can do.
它將會像地獄般的疼痛 而且你不能壓傷口  可至少你可以走了.
lt'll hurt like hell and you can't put any weight on it, but at least you can move.
他們幾個世紀前就來過了. 捆在這兒的人都會變成骨架.
They combed these mountains centuries ago. Anyone trapped would be a skeleton now.
這只是看起來而已.  什麼?
That is just what it looked like.  What?
莎拉以為她看到一個人了.  S看到什麼?
Sarah thinks she saw someone.  Saw what?
不是以為, 我確實看到了一個人.
l don't think l saw someone, l saw someone.
不是這樣的, 你聽到了怪聲 然後在心理作用下"看到了".
No, you heard something and saw what you wanted to see.
現在很黑. 使人產生幻覺.  我可以確切地描述我所看到的.
lt's the dark. lt plays tricks on people.  l can describe exactly what l saw.
你看到什麼了?  一個人,我看到一個人.
What did you see?  A man. l saw a man.
你確定?  如假包換!
REBECCA: Are you sure?  Yes!
而且這不是第一次了.  我認為我以前看到過, 但是現在我確定了.
And it's not the first time. l thought l saw someone before, but now l'm sure.
如果有人在這兒的話, 可能會幫助我們出去
Look, if there is somebody down here, then maybe they can help get us out.
沙拉,這兒沒人. 忘了它吧!
Sarah, there's noone down here. Forget about it!
我們得把霍麗從這兒移走.
Hey, we have to get Holly out of here.
好不好? 這是我們的當務之急.
OK? This is all that matters right now.
貝絲!  沒事了.
Beth!  lt's OK.
是嗎!媽的
ls it? Fuck!
媽的.
Fuck me.
你得保持體溫.
SAM: You've got to keep warm.
為什麼走開了? 太陽光在那兒.
BETH: Why are we walking away? There was daylight back there.
這不是太陽光. 它是4A84A4D8里的磷發出的光.
JUNO: lt wasn't. lt was phosphorus in the rock.
我們在地表的兩公里以下, 這兒唯一的光是我們發出來的.
We're two miles underground, the only light down here is ours.
看起來陽光就他媽在我眼前
HOLLY: Argh! Well, it looked like fucking daylight to me.
走對了!
Right tunnel!
我扶著你,好嗎?
l got you. OK? (Holly moans)
(Groans in pain)
耶穌啊! 這是什麼地方?
BETH: Jesus! What is this place?
霍麗, 紅外線開關在哪兒??
Holly, where's the infrared button?
動物屍體.
SARAH: Dead animals.
成百上千.
Hundreds of them.
姑娘們,這可不是什麼好兆頭.
BETH: This is not good, guys.
我們能從這兒出去嗎?走哪條路?
REBECCA: Can we get out of here? Which way?
快點.
Come on.
我不知道.  你不知道?這是什麼意思?
l don't know. BETH: What do you mean, you don't know?
一點風也沒有.  任何一條隧道都有可能是, 選一個吧.
There's no breeze. lt could be any one of these tunnels. Take your pick.
媽的,喂!
Oh, fuck it! Hello!
不要這樣!  有人在嗎?
Please!  ls there anybody there?
喂!
Hello!
(Screams)
在那兒! 在上面! 在牆壁上面!
JUNO: lt's there! lt's up there! lt's there on the roof!
他媽的地獄, 你看到...? 那他媽是什麼?
Fucking hell, did you see...? What the fuck was that?
不知道! 他移動的很快,我很難看清它!
l don't know! lt moved so fast, l could barely see it!
我從未看到有人想他那樣爬!  我早就告訴你我看到個人了!
l've never seen anyone climb like that!  l told you l saw someone!
這不是人!  夠了.
That was not a human being!  Screw this.
咱們挑一條路碰碰運氣吧. 走!
Let's take our chances and pick a tunnel. Move!
(Screeching)
發生什麼事了?
What's happening?
媽的! 他把我們包圍了.
Oh, shit! lt's circling us.
它在哪兒?  這條路!快!
Where is it?  This way! Move!
霍麗,我們得走了.  快,走!
Holly! We've got to move. We've got to move.  Come on! Move it!
霍麗,快點! 走了,快
JUNO: Come on, Holly! Move it! Let's go!
朱諾,火焰棒! 仍了它!  媽的!
Juno, the flare! Get rid of it!  Fuck!
霍麗, 一直走,快 !
JUNO: Holly, keep moving, come on! (Holly groans)
霍麗!霍麗!
Holly! Holly!
莎拉!
Sarah!
霍麗!
Holly!
莎拉!
Sarah!
莎拉! 快跑!
Sarah! Run!
莎拉!
Sarah!
滾開!
Get off!
滾開, 你他媽的!
Get away, you fucker!
(Screeches)
(Juno hyperventilates)
(Whimpers)
不要拋下我.
Don't leave me.
媽的,我的電池沒電了.
Oh, fuck. My battery's gone dead.
他們在哪兒?
Where are they?
其他人出什麼事了?
What's happened to the others?
貝卡請告訴我我們將要離開這個鬼地方.
Becca, please say we're gonna get out of here.
好.
OK. OK.
OK.
走!
Go. Go!
媽咪,媽咪.
JESSlCA: (Whispers) Mummy. Mummy.
如果你真的準備...
lf you're really ready...
(Coughs and splutters)
(Growling)
(Screeching)
(Low howl)
媽的.
Oh, fuck. Fuck.
關了手電.
Turn the light off.
安靜.
Quiet.
(Squelching)
(Retches)
(Growls)
(Screeches)
莎拉! 莎拉!
JUNO: Sarah! Sarah!
莎拉!
Sarah!
他看不到我們.
lt can't see us.
(Beeping)
薩姆? 貝卡?
Sam? Becca?
貝卡!
Becca! (Echoes)
貝卡!  我是朱諾.
Becca!  lt's Juno.
貝卡!
JUNO: Becca!
她正在發出的聲音會把 這兒的每一隻這種東西吸引到她頭上去.
The noise she's making, she'll bring every one of those things down on her head.
只要不是吸引到我頭上.
As long as it's not on mine.
貝卡!
Becca!
薩姆!
Sam!
JUNO: Sam!
薩姆!
Sam!
有人嗎?
Anyone?
薩姆!
Sam!
對不起.對不起.
l'm sorry. l'm sorry.
哦...
Oh...
對不起.
l'm sorry.
媽的.
Fuck. OK.
好.
OK.
安全！.
lt's all clear.
(Screeches)
薩姆，快跑!
Sam, run!
(Screeches)
我們聽到你為莎拉哭泣.
We heard you crying for Sarah.
其他人在哪兒?
Where are the others?
他們... 他們帶走了霍麗.
They... They took Holly.
貝絲...
Beth...
Beth已經死了.
Beth's dead.
(Juno sobs)
薩姆...
Sam...
..這是什麼東西?
..what is that thing?
我不知道.不過，他們確實像人.
l don't know. Well, it does look human.
趕快，我們得在這些東西找到我們之前 找到路出去.
Come on, we need to find the way out before those things find us.
不.
No.
薩姆 ，告訴我們怎麼跟他鬥.
Sam, tell us what we're fighting.
恩..
Well...
..他們完全瞎了.
..they're totally blind.
從我們已經看到的來推斷, 我認為他們用聲音來捕獵. 就像蝙蝠一樣.
And judging from what we've seen, l'd say they use sound to hunt with. Like a bat.
他們已經進化到 非常適應生活在漆黑的這兒.
And they've evolved perfectly to live down here in the dark.
不管他們是什麼, 他們到地面捕捉獵物.
Whatever they are, they go to the surface to hunt.
他們把獵物帶到這兒來吃, 通過一個入口.
And they bring their food back down here to eat, through an entrance.
聽著，如果我們足夠安靜 並且躲過這些笨蛋...
Listen, if we can stay quiet enough and evade these fuckers...
..我想我找到出去的方法了.
..l think l found the way out.
你怎麼看?
You think?
我們已經發現了一些攀登齒輪， 不管是誰帶下來的 ，給我們標出了路.
The climbing gear we found  whoever brought that down here marked their route.
我找到這些標記了  那我們還等什麼呢?
l found those markings.  Well, what are we waiting for?
莎拉
Sarah.
找不到莎拉，我不會走.
l'm not leaving without Sarah.
莎拉!
(Gasps) Sarah!
天啦.
Oh, God.
天啦  不.
Oh, God. No.
莎拉...
Sarah...
我會帶你出去.
l'm getting you out of here.
(Groans in agony)
不要碰我. 不要碰我.
Don't touch me. Don't touch me.
我聽到朱諾叫我.
l heard Juno calling me.
我去找她, 然後我們回來救你.
l'm gonna go and find her, and we're gonna come back and get you out.
不，離她遠一點.
No, stay away from her.
什麼?  我變成這樣都是她害的.
What?  She did this to me.
什麼?  她遺棄了我.
What?  She left me.
不是, 他不會這樣的. 不是.
No, she didn't. No.
莎拉 莎拉...
Shh.  Sarah...
(Gurgles)
不要相信她.
Don't trust her.
你自己找出路吧.
You find your own way out.
沒事了
lt's OK. lt's all right.
貝絲，我不會拋下你的 我不會拋下你的.
l'm not gonna leave you, Beth. l'm not gonna leave you.
我不會把你拋在這兒不管的
l'm not leaving you here, OK?
貝絲，到這兒來
Come here. Beth!
這是朱諾的.
This is Juno's.
這是從保羅那兒來的
lt's from Paul.
不.
Oh, no.
對不起.
Sorry.
(Sobs)
(Distant screeching)
它們來了.求求你跟我一起走吧.
Please... Oh, that's them. Please, come with me.
求你了.
Please.
莎拉...
Sarah...
..不要這樣離開我.
..don't leave me like this.
不，求你不要讓我這麼做.
No, please don't ask me to do that.
求你了. 我不能，我不能這麼做t.
Please.  l can't. l can't do that.
我不能這麼做
l can't do that.
求你了.
Please.
好吧.
OK. Ssh.
閉上眼睛.
Close your eyes.
(Panting)
(Screeches)
(Screech)
(Crawler squeals and whimpers)
(Growls)
(Screeches)
(Screams)
Hurry! Move!
莎拉?
Sarah?
朱諾,她死了, 我們不能再等她了.
Look, she's dead, Juno. We can't wait for her.
快走!
Come on!
莎拉!
JUNO: Sarah!
Sarah!
莎拉?
Sarah?
快跑!
Run!  (Screeching)
媽的!
Oh, fuck!
(Groans with exertion)
媽的.
Fuck.
快!  朱諾， 攔住她。 我會跟著你!
Come on!  Juno, stop her! l'll be right behind you!
薩姆! 你在幹什麼?
Sam! What are you doing?
快回來!
Come back!
貝卡!
Becca!
你沒有足夠的繩子!
You haven't got enough rope!
薩姆! 塊掉頭!
Sam! Turn around!
你這是在幹嘛?塊轉回來!  薩姆, 寶貝!
What are you doing? Turn around!  Sam, baby!
薩姆!薩姆!  薩姆! 快回來. 你回得來的.
Sam! Sam!  Sam, turn around. You can come back.
寶貝，求你了, 請聽我的!
Please, baby, listen to me. Please!
薩姆!
Sam!
不!
No!
你到底想幹什麼?
What are you doing?
薩姆
Sam!
薩姆! 不!
Sam! No!
(Screeches)
你怎麼了?
What happened to you?
麗貝卡?
Rebecca?
貝絲呢?
What about Beth?
別提了.
Didn't make it.
你看見她死了?
You saw her die?
走吧.
Come on.
趕快.
Come on. Come on.
(Distant screeching)
(Screeching)
(Juno screams)
不，天啦!
No! No!
(Gasps)
天啦!
Oh, God!
(Horn blares)
(Distant screeching)